## **Garvit Pahal**

g10pahal@gmail.com • +91 8953454203 https://github.com/gpahal • https://linkedin.com/in/gpahal

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with 10 years of experience building products 0-1 and beyond. I love working in teams that value excellence, customer delight, and iteration speed. I'm excited about how AI will change our lives and work in the next few years.

## **EDUCATION**

#### INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT), KANPUR

Kanpur, India

# Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

2012 - 2016

- Cumulative Performance Index (CPI) of 9.6/10
- Secured All India Rank of 196 in IIT-JEE 2012 (99.97 percentile)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### INDEPENDENT SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT AND RESEARCH

Bengaluru, India Aug 2024 - Present

- Built voice customer support agents for B2C finance and quick commerce companies
- Trained a micro GPT model: gpahal/microgpt
- Researching multi modal retrieval and AI: gpahal/pdf-rag-embed-bench
- Built a simple, durable and resilient workflow engine library ideal for AI workflows: gpahal/durable-execution

# GM LABS Founding Software Engineer

Bengaluru, India

Apr 2022 - Apr 2024

- Built Perch Spotify for reading long-form content, Perch AMA tool for creators, Startup Archive curated startup advice from the world's best founders, gm.xyz a place to host your web3 community
- Architected and led the backend and infrastructure. Contributed to the web and mobile apps

#### **HARNESS**

Bengaluru, India

#### Founding Staff Software Engineer

Apr 2019 - Aug 2021

- Harness helps take your code from GitHub to production easily, quickly and resiliently. Made for large enterprises
- Built the workflow engine powering Harness's software delivery platform, supporting durable multi-week workflows
- Helped transition a monolithic app to a microservices deployment, leading to multiple new product launches
- The company grew 50x in revenue and went from a single product to 6

#### ALPHAGREP SECURITIES

Bengaluru, India

# Quant Researcher and Trading Analyst

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

- AlphaGrep is a quantitative trading and investment firm
- Researched and developed high-frequency quantitative trading strategies (linear regression statistical arbitrage) for commodity markets in China, which became my team's most profitable market

#### **DGRAPH**

Bengaluru, India Nov 2017 - Jun 2018

# Founding Software Engineer

Dgraph is one of the most popular open-source distributed graph databases

- Launched Ratel, Dgraph's data visualisation and cluster management interface
- Launched database clients in JavaScript and Python. Maintained client libraries for other languages
- Laid groundwork for the Dgraph-as-a-service platform built on top of Kubernetes

# **PLATO**

Bengaluru, India Jul 2015 - Sep 2017

## Founder

- Plato is a chat app for one-on-one career mentoring
- Conducted successful pilots during college placements and entrepreneurship events
- Funded by Commence Mint. Secured 2nd position in Microsoft Imagine Cup, India (2015) and were incubated at IIT Kanpur

SUPERSTREAM Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

• Superstream is a protocol and a collection of SDKs for real-time money streaming on Solana. It allows anyone to continuously send money to anyone else at any interval up to a second.

- Designed, implemented, and deployed it on devnet, testnet and mainnet clusters of Solana
- The project is open source and documented at <u>superstream.finance</u>

#### PROGRAMMING TUTORING SYSTEM

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014

- Research project under Dr Sumit Gulwani (Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research, Redmond) and Prof. Amey Karkare (Assistant Professor, IIT Kanpur)
- Launched command line and web apps to assist in teaching introductory programming courses in the 1st year of college by automating assignment and feedback generation and solution-checking
- Project deployed in the 2014-15 academic year (with 400+ enrolled students)

## AREAS OF INTEREST

- AI, Information retrieval, Databases, Distributed Systems, Programming Languages
- Industries: Developer Tools, Software Infrastructure, Finance, Health, Education, Productivity

#### AWARDS AND SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received Academic Excellence awards (2013, 2014, 2015) for outstanding performance in academics at IIT Kanpur
- Secured an All India Rank of 196 in the IIT entrance exam in 2012 out of 500,000 applicants (99.97 percentile)
- Qualified for the Indian National Mathematics Olympiad in 2010 and 2011 by securing 2nd and 5th state rank
- Received the prestigious Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana (KVPY) from the Department of Science and Technology, Government of India